Guide to the photograph album RAF tour on MV Dilwara - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref159
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
RAF tour on MV Dilwara - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection
1934 - 1939
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939
AD.MC.030_ref159
42 Leaves - 88 gelatin silver prints and 4 cartoons
Photograph album containing 88 prints and 4 cartoons created by officer Les Wells while he served with the RAF Medical Service as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command and whilst he was stationed in Abu Qir (Aboukir), Egypt between 1934 and 1939. The album contains photographs of three ships; MV Dilwara (her maiden voyage in March 1936), HT Somersetshire and HMS Enterprise and ports including Karachi and Aden. There are also a number of photographs of the Nouzha Gardens in Alexandria Loose photographs at the end of the album include one of RAF servicemen and women at RAF Hinaidi. See also Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells, part of the Hisham Khatib Collection.
Object Digital Copy Only - ref159
Conditions Governing Access
Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Dr. Hisham Khatib are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from repository. Please contact Akkasah at akkasah@nyu.edu
Photographic Prints; Iraq; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Royal Air Force; Egypt; Military/Soldiers; Boats/Ships; Abu Qir, Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Alexandria, Egypt; Aden, Yemen; Karachi, Pakistan; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Front Cover of RAF tour on MV Dilwara - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1939; ref159_000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
- Inside of the front cover: The MV Dilwara and an RAF Medical Services emblem with the motto 'Nec Aspera Terrent'., 1936-1939; ref159_000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Seas; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Medals/Insignia
- Top Left: A train carriage with some men in military uniform in the foreground. Top Right: The river Shatt al-Arab, Bottom: Kites in Basra., 1936-1939; ref159_000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Trains; Birds; Seas; Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Baghdad, Iraq; Basra, Iraq; Animals; Rivers; Transportation; Group Portraits
- Top Left: Ships at Abadan Oil Refinery. Bottom Left: H.T Dilwara on her maiden voyage. Top Right, Bottom Right: Karachi Harbour, 1936-1939; ref159_000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Seas; Ports; Karachi, Pakistan; Abadan, Khuzestan Province, Iran; Petroleum industry and trade.; Transportation
- Top Left, Top Right: H.T. Somersetshire in Karachi. Bottom Left, Bottom Right: People loading cargo on the H.T Dilwara., 1936-1939; ref159_000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Seas; Buildings; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Karachi, Pakistan; Transportation; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Several ships off the coast of Aden., 1936-1939; ref159_000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Aden, Yemen; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Seas; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Coast; Transportation
- Top Left: A ship on guard during the Abyssinian Crisis. Top Right: Steamer Point, Aden. Bottom Left, Bottom Right: H.M.S Enterprise, 1936-1939; ref159_000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Seas; Mountains/Hills; Aden, Yemen; Coast; Transportation; Military/Soldiers; Airplanes; Ethiopia; Landscapes
- Top Left: Royal Air Force sick quarters. Top Right: Eastern bay of Aboukir. Bottom Left, Bottom Right: People fishing sardines in the western bay, 1936-1939; ref159_000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Fishing; Men; Beaches; Buildings; Abu Qir, Egypt; Military/Soldiers; Coast; Buildings; Hospitals; Landscapes; Group Portraits
- Top Left, Top Right, Bottom Right: Canons. Bottom Left: Royal Air Force Headquarters in Aboukir., 1936-1939; ref159_000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Cannons; Royal Air Force; Flags; Palm Trees; Buildings; Guns; Children; Abu Qir, Egypt; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Women; Children; Boys; Regional/National Dress
- People fishing, mending fishing nets and a decorated boat., 1936-1939; ref159_000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Fishing; Buildings; Men; Buildings; Transportation; Flags; Regional/National Dress; Seas; Group Portraits
- Top left and right: The western bay of Abu Qir. Top centre: Les Wells. Bottom left and right: Archaeological site at Canopus. Bottom centre: A child., 1936-1939; ref159_000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; English Writing; Men; Children; Landscapes; Beaches; Boats/Ships; Seas; Individual Portraits; Abu Qir, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Coast; Girls
- Several photographs of Nouzha Gardens in Alexandria., 1936-1939; ref159_000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Gardens; Water; Parks; Palm Trees; Statues/Sculptures; Landscapes
- Several photographs of Nouzha Gardens in Alexandria., 1936-1939; ref159_000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Gardens; Parks; Statues/Sculptures; Palm Trees; Ponds; Water; Landscapes
- Several photographs of Nouzha Gardens in Alexandria., 1936-1939; ref159_000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Gardens; Parks; Palm Trees; Birds; Animals; Lakes; Landscapes
- Several photographs of the zoo in Nouzha Gardens, Alexandria., 1936-1939; ref159_000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Zoos; Animals
- Several photographs of the zoo in Nouzha Gardens, Alexandria., 1936-1939; ref159_000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Zoos; Animals; Birds
- Top Left, Top Right: Ships at Mahmoudiyah canal, Bottom Left, Bottom Right: Ships at Alexandria Harbour., 1936-1939; ref159_000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Seas; Boats/Ships; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Ports; Canals; Buildings; Transportation; Buildings
- Top and bottom left: Sand-yachts and a sand-yacht club at 4 FTS Abu Suweir Air Base (RAF Abu Sueir). Bottom right: Pyramid and Sphinx of Giza., 1936-1939; ref159_000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; English Writing; Deserts; Transportation; Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Men; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Transportation; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Abu Suweir, Egypt; Ismailia, Egypt; Group Portraits
- Pyramids of Giza and the Sphinx of Giza., 1936-1939; ref159_000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; English Writing; Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; Men; Religious Sites; Landscapes
- Cairo Station, the Nahdet Misr statue and Zoological gardens in Cairo., 1936-1939; ref159_000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; English Writing; Railways; Buildings; Zoos; Animals; Statues/Sculptures; Lakes; Palm Trees; Carriages/Coaches; Architecture; Buildings; Flags; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
- Several photographs of Giza Zoo, Montaza Palace and the interior of a church., 1936-1939; ref159_000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Elephants; Animals; Buildings; Palaces; Palm Trees; Churches; Zoos; Palaces; Alexandria, Egypt; Elephants; Religious Sites
- Several photographs of the ruins of Canopus and a cemetery., 1936-1939; ref159_000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Abu Qir, Egypt; Cemeteries; Landscapes
- Top Left: A Wing Commander and Flying Officer of the RAF. Top RIght: A man standing with a donkey. Bottom Left: RAF buildings. Bottom Right: A Hawker Hart KG416 military aircraft., 1936-1939; ref159_000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Abu Qir, Egypt; English Writing; Airplanes; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Donkeys; Animals; Group Portraits; Buildings; Royal Air Force; Transportation
- Top Left: An RAF building Top Right: Eastern bay Abu Qir. Bottom Left: A Bristol Blenheim military aircraft. Bottom Right: Les Wells posing with a military aircraft., 1936-1939; ref159_000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Palm Trees; Buildings; Transportation; Airplanes; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Abu Qir, Egypt; Coast; Medals/Insignia
- Top: Team portrait of a hockey team including Les Wells in the front row, far right. Bottom: Hockey players on the field., 1938; ref159_000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Sports; Egypt; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Team Portrait of a hockey team., 1939; ref159_000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Group Portraits; Men; Sports; Outdoors; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Cairo desert road., 1936-1939; ref159_000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Landscapes; Deserts; Streets/Roads; English Writing
- Top: Tents and cars in the desert. Bottom: A group of young men posing with a car on the side of the road., 1936-1939; ref159_000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Egypt; Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Landscapes; Deserts; Tents; Transportation; Cars/Trucks
- Several photographs from "Aboukir Turf Club meeting"., 1938; ref159_000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Abu Qir, Egypt; English Writing; Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Brass Instruments; Musical Instruments; Animals; Donkeys; Costumes; Marching Band; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Medals/Insignia
- Top Left: A group of men and a child with donkeys. Bottom Left: A multi-generational group. Right: A portrait of Les Wells., 1936-1939; ref159_000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Donkeys; Animals; Buildings; Houses; Women; Boys; Children; Royal Air Force
- A man in a military uniform looking through a microscope., 1936-1939; ref159_000031; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Military/Soldiers; Scientific Equipment; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Royal Air Force; Medals/Insignia
- A drawing of two men in military uniforms with the caption "Excused guards for what?"., 1936-1939; ref159_000032; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Unknown Locations; English Writing; Musical Instruments; Military/Soldiers; Men; Dogs; Animals; Guns; Weapons; Art; Printed Materials
- A drawing of a child-like man in military uniform leading a canon and man in military uniform repairing an aircraft with the caption "Sweating on your third, corporal?", 1936-1939; ref159_000033; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Unknown Locations; English Writing; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Children; Men; Transportation; Airplanes; Art; Children; Printed Materials
- A drawing showing the extermination of Insects through paraffin., 1936-1939; ref159_000034; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Egypt; English Writing; Women; Art; Printed Materials
- A drawing showing a man ordering Horlicks in a casino., 1936-1939; ref159_000035; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Men; English Writing; Women; Casinos; Musical Instruments; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages; Art; Printed Materials
- Men gathered for the "Aboukir Turf Club"., December 1937; ref159_000036; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Abu Qir, Egypt; English Writing; Men; Outdoors; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Christmas; Group Portraits
- Several men sitting on donkeys for a race., 1937-1938; ref159_000037; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Outdoors; Donkeys; Animals; Buildings; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Costumes; Christmas; Group Portraits
- A crowd watching a competition., Circa 1937-1938; ref159_000038; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Men; Women; Outdoors; Transportation; Carriages/Coaches; Costumes; Children; Group Portraits
- A crowd watching a competition., Circa 1937-1938; ref159_000039; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Men; Women; Children; Outdoors; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Buildings; Costumes; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits
- People dressed up as horses and a coachman., Circa 1937-1938; ref159_000040; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Outdoors; Costumes; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits
- Winners of the competitive costume competition receiving prizes, Circa 1937-1938; ref159_000041; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Men; Children; Outdoors; Donkeys; Animals; Uniforms; Awards; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Group Portraits
- A group portrait of the Coldstream Guards harmonica band., 1936-1939; ref159_000042; Studio H. (Hakob) Dilekyan, Alexandria (Egypt) (Circa 1930s-1940s); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; String Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Woodwind Instruments; Musical Instruments; Buildings; Uniforms; Musicians; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers; English Writing
- Inside of the back cover, 1936-1939; ref159_000043; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
- Back cover of RAF tour on MV Dilwara - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1936-1939; ref159_000044; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
- A group portrait of RAF service men and women in uniform., 1936-1939; ref159_000045; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Women; Men; Uniforms; Outdoors; English Writing; Nurses; Military/Soldiers; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Medals/Insignia
- A group portrait of RAF service men and women at RAF Hinaidi., 1934; ref159_000046; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Outdoors; Uniforms; Nurses; Military/Soldiers; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Nurses
- A group portrait of men in uniforms., 1936-1939; ref159_000047; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Uniforms; English Writing; Unknown Locations; Sports; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force
- Several boats off the coast of Malta., 1936-1939; ref159_000048; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Men; Outdoors; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Malta
- A group of four men., 1936-1939; ref159_000049; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- A man reclining with a cigarette in his hand., 1936-1939; ref159_000050; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Unknown Locations; Cigarettes; Smoking
- Men and women at the Western Wall., 1936-1939; ref159_000051; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jerusalem; Men; Women; Outdoors; Regional/National Dress; Religious Sites; Western Wall; Palestine; Praying; Group Portraits; Turbans
- The Western Wall., 1936-1939; ref159_000052; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - ref159)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jerusalem; Men; Outdoors; Praying; Religious Sites; Western Wall; Palestine; Group Portraits
- Flamingoes at Nouzha Zoo (from ref159_000015)., ref159_000054
  Birds; Zoos; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Animals